Chandrima Raha 🕡 Featured

Software Developer seeking roles in Software Engineering, Software
Development, Project Management, Change Management, Defect Management, Quality
Management, Requirement Gathering, Application Support, ASP. Net
MVC, JavaScript, SQL Server, JIRA, TFS, Git



Current Designation: Software Developer Total Experience: 5 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: TietoEvry Notice Period: 2 Months

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computers]

Pref. Location: Germany, United Kingdom (UK), Bengaluru /

Bangalore

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Software Developer, Software Engineering, Software Development, Project Management, Change Management, Defect Management, Quality Management, Requirement Gathering, Application Support, ASP. Net

MVC, JavaScript, SQL Server, JIRA, TFS, Git

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 19-Jan-21 Last Modified: 19-Jan-21

Summary

Presently, working in TietoEvry as a Software Developer having nearly 5 years of experience in .Net framework. I have worked on MVC .Net, ASP .Net, Web APIs and currently working on MS Blazor with .Net Framework and SQL Server. Handled development of several banking applications, worked on various code enhancements based on client requirements.

Work Experience

TietoEvry as Software Developer

Dec 2019 to Till Date

Working in Banking & Insurance domain in developing and structuring web portal.

Developing employee management portal of a well-known bank using MS Blazor with .Net framework.

Using web API to gather data, insert, update and delete. User Authentication is also performed for login purposes.

Technologies: MVC .Net, Blazor with .Net, Web API and using SQL Server for Database.

Tata Consultancy Services Limited as System Engineer

Mar 2019 to Nov 2019

Worked in banking project, handled employee information and awards for employees relating to promotional aspects.

Monitoring and Improvement of the website's features, growth and customer targeting pages.

Extraction of data in MS-SQL Server and transformed the data based on business requirements using MVC .Net and load into target Database.

Technologies: MVC .Net and using SQL Server for Database, ServiceNow, Autosys

Indusnet Technologies Pvt Ltd as System Engineer

Jan 2017 to Feb 2019

Worked in several banking, insurance and travel projects.

Handled client communication, development and enhancement of portals and performed Manual Testing. Worked in MVC .Net, ASP .Net, Web APIs etc.

Technologies- Jira, Advance MS Excel, MVC .Net, ASP .Net,

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from West Bengal University of Technology (WBUT) in 2015

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

Java Certification

PHP and MySQL certification

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
JIRA, TFS, DevOps, SQL Server	
MS Office(Outlook,Word,Excel,PowerPoint)	
ASP .Net, MVC .Net, MySQL, PHP	
GIT, Service now, Microsoft 365,	

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				
Bengali				
French				

Affirmative Action

Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

Job Type: Permanent / Temporary

Employment Status: Full Time, Part Time